Peppino Mangravite
Archives of American Art, Smithsonian Institution
- Miscellaneous Records, 1926-1974, undated, Series 5:; (Boxes 4, 8; 10 folders; Reel 5881)
  Miscellaneous records consist of art work, scattered biographical information and financial records, and two sound recordings. Art work consists of a small number of sketches by Mangravite and greeting cards with original prints by John [illegible], Clare Romano and John Ross, and an ink drawing by M.S. Additional sound recordings are found in Series 3: Interviews with Artists.
  - Art Work (Box 4, Reel 5881)
    - Sketches by Mangravite, 1942-1950s, undated (Box 4, Reel 5881)
    - Greeting Cards with Original Art Work, 1953, undated (Box 4, Reel 5881)
  - Biographical Information, 1926-1974, undated (Box 4, Reel 5881)
  - Financial Records (Box 4, Reel 5881)
    - Gallery Statements and Accounts (Dudensing and Rehn), 1928-1972, undated (Box 4, Reel 5881)
    - Receipts for Art Deliveries, 1938-1965 (Box 4, Reel 5881)
    - Receipts for Payments to Mangravite, 1935-1951, undated (Box 4, Reel 5881)
    - Receipts, Miscellaneous, 1932-1974, undated (Box 4, Reel 5881)
  - Fine Arts Insurance Policy; Fine Arts Schedule, 1965-1968, undated (Box 4, Reel 5881)
  - Lease for Office at 2 East 23rd Street, New York City, Dec. 15, 1938-Jan. 31, 1939 (Box 4, Reel 5881)
  - Audio/Visual Records (Box 8 (sol), Reel 5881)
    - "Art in Education," WNYC radio broadcast of Peppino Mangravite and George Picken, October 11, 1953, (33-1/3 rpm recording) (Box 8 (sol), Reel 5881)
    - At the Art Studio of the Potomac School, P. Mangravite," undated, (one 10 ½" reel of 16-mm color silent motion picture film) (Box 8 (sol), Reel 5881)
- Printed Matter, 1918-1982, and undated, Series 6:; (Box 4-6; 2.65 linear ft.; Reels 5881-5882)
  - Articles About/Mentioning Mangravite, 1932-1974, undated (Box 4, Reel 5881)
  - Articles By Mangravite, 1926-1965, (2 folders) (Box 4, Reel 5881)
  - Articles on Miscellaneous Art-Related Topics, 1940-1978, undated (Box 4, Reel unfilmed)
  - Exhibition Announcements, 1928-1975, undated, (2 folders) (Box 4, Reel 5881)
  - Exhibition Catalogs for Mangravite Exhibitions, 1921-1939, (15 folders) (Box 4, Reel 5881)
  - Exhibition Catalogs for Mangravite Exhibitions, 1940-1982, undated, (22 folders) (Box 5, Reel 5881-5882)
  - Exhibition Catalogs for Mangravite on Jury, 1941-1964, undated (Box 5, Reel 5881-5882)
  - Exhibition Catalogs for Other Artists' Exhibitions, 1952-1977, undated, (2 folders) (Box 6 (hol), Reel unfilmed)
  - Announcements of Mangravite Lectures, Conference Participation, etc., 1936-1969, undated (Box 6 (hol), Reel 5882)
  - Printed Materials for Events and Organizations Sponsored/Endorsed by Mangravite, 1933-1948, undated (Box 6 (hol), Reel 5882)
  - Miscellaneous Items, Art-Related, 1935-1959, undated (Box 6 (hol), Reel unfilmed)
  - Miscellaneous Items, Not Art-Related, 1933-1967, undated (Box 6 (hol), Reel unfilmed)
  - Miscellaneous Items Mentioning Mangravite, 1923-1953, undated (Box 6 (hol), Reel 5882)
  - Prospectuses for Exhibitions Juried by Mangravite, 1953 (Box 6 (hol), Reel 5882)
  - Prospectuses for Miscellaneous Exhibitions, 1939-1968 (Box 6 (hol), Reel unfilmed)
  - School Catalogs and Brochures for Courses Taught by Mangravite, 1919-1969, undated (Box 6 (hol), Reel 5882)
- Photographs, circa 1926-circa 1970, and undated, Series 7:; (Boxes 7-8; 0.6 linear ft.; Reel 5882)
  - Mangravite, circa 1970s (Box 7 (hol), Reel 5882)
  - Mangravite with Neapolitan Newspaper Critics, 1945 (Box 7 (hol), Reel 5882)
  - Mangravite with Other Artists, circa 1936-1950s, undated (Box 7 (hol), Reel 5882)
  - Mangravite with Others (unidentified), undated (Box 7 (hol), Reel 5882)
  - Mangravite with Students, circa 1926-1942 (Box 7 (hol), Reel 5882)
  - Other Artists (Alfo Basaldella and Robert Laurent), 1955 (Box 7 (hol), Reel 5882)
  - Mr. and Mrs. Laurance Roberts [of the American Academy in Rome], 1955 (Box 7 (hol), Reel 5882)
  - Students, circa 1926 (Box 7 (hol), Reel 5882)
  - Murals By Mangravite (Box 7 (hol), Reel 5882)
    - Club in Colorado Springs, circa 1937-1938 (Box 7 (hol), Reel 5882)
    - Columbia University Men's Faculty Club (with key to figures and symbols), undated (Box 7 (hol), Reel 5882)
    - Governor's Mansion, Virgin Islands, undated (Box 7 (hol), Reel 5882)
    - St. Anthony's Shrine, Boston, Mass., 1955 (Box 7 (hol), Reel 5882)
    - U.S. Post Office, Atlantic City, N.J., 1935 (Box 7 (hol), Reel 5882)
    - U.S. Post Office, Hempstead, N.Y., 1933, (see also: box 8) (Box 7 (hol), Reel 5882)
    - U.S. Post Office, Jackson Heights, Flushing, N.Y., circa 1930s (Box 7 (hol), Reel 5882)
    - Sketch for Unidentified, Unexecuted Mural, undated (Box 7 (hol), Reel 5882)
  - Paintings By Mangravite (Box 7 (hol), Reel 5882)
    - Exhibition Installation Views including Paintings by Mangravite, undated (Box 7 (hol), Reel 5882)
    - Carnegie Institute and unidentified (Box 7 (hol), Reel 5882)
    - Paintings, undated (Box 7 (hol), Reel 5882)
  - Paintings, Duplicate Prints and Negative, undated (Box 7 (hol), Reel unfilmed)
  - Sculpture by Edgar Britton, 1947-1951 (Box 7 (hol), Reel 5882)
  - Murals By Other Artists, U.S. Post Office, Hempstead, NY, 1933 (Box 8 (sol), Reel 5882)